Jhal
Hello Hello Friends My name is Amit and
today we will be watching Aditya Life Insurance
's Episode Income Plan We will look at the features of this plan,
review its illustrations and try to calculate its rate of return
because it is a
guaranteed savings plan, so what rate
of return is it giving you, what is its death benefit,
what is its surrender value and its
features, we will look at all these things in today's video, so
let's start with the
definition of subscription, this 1995
Individual Life Insurance means that it is
not from the market, not participating, which means that
it will not get any bonus from the company
that you
can share with your partner or anyone else, subscribe,
subscribe, then there is
no bill in this, then you will
get guaranteed returns and those guaranteed
returns will be told to you in the beginning what will be the
guarantee and how you
can see it, I will cover this in the video,
so stay tuned to the video, if we
look at the features of this plan further, then
they say that the features are long-term
interest getting  You will keep getting subscription
like the minister, your option benefit
option is an option and if you subscribe
for your love,
you get a total subscription of Rs 10 lakh for 10 years,
but some people want
that they should get this Rs 10 lakh back as well, it is
said that they will get Rs 10 lakh back, they did
not use this, there are
loyalty additions due to which the
amount will keep increasing in your maturity benefit, we will
understand this in an example, competition
fights that if you
want to buy any future value then you
can mute your volume,
by example I mean you will keep getting scanner benefit, let us
assume that you can subscribe if
you want, you can subscribe, for example, if you want Rs
5500, you do not
want to subscribe, then subscribe, thank you, take a look
here and the minimum maximum
cannot be subscribed,
if we talk about the premium payment term, the
policy term is given here in a very good way, the
premium payment
term is 6 years, 8 years, 12 years,
you get three options, this is the time  There is a duration
for which you will pay at a minimum, that is, you will pay
premium for six years, you will pay premium
for eight years, you will pay premium for 12 years. The policy term
is the term till which you will get the death benefit, which will be
your time shot. You will understand its meaning
when we cover the illustration,
but here for example, you will
see that your policy term is till one year after that, that is,
you have policy term for one year extra than the period for which you have paid premium. In other words,
till this time you will get the death
benefit, whatever will be your time shot
benefit, and the period is that if you survive
this time, whatever your policy
terms are, if you survive then from then onwards
you will start getting regular income.
If you have
chosen the tenure of 6, then you will just subscribe till
2025. Option A
is the option to subscribe within 12 years.
Payment Denials your Fish and accordingly it will be charged,
if you use it then
you will not be charged, but you do it.  So you
cannot subscribe to the channel on that, but
whenever you are taking it, then first somehow do
this that you want the
insurance of Rs 5.5 lakh, there is no value for you,
for which we will do such a big thing, due to this there are
benefit options to give benefit option
which we are covering, so you have to
choose the option whether you want to take turn of
milk, you want to reach your PM, there is
no premium payment option, policy
time benefit fee period, I saw inside the table above them, from that
you have the option of
frequency, you want its meaning
or you want to wear jewellery, you
can select this, you will subscribe if
you have at least Rs 10 lakh, your debit will be
total prepaid 90, if you have
submitted a total of Rs 5 lakh till now, you will get at least one paper with
you, but if you click
then it goes up to Rs 10 lakh, then
you will get this from this, if you have taken the policy, then I
told you that if the value of that time is
more than these two, then you will get it,
if out of these two you will get whichever
is the nearest multiple of the subsidy, at this stage you
take this policy accordingly
They have taken the factor but there is a very
simple way to do it fast that you
go to their site and there is a hill station
Saturday benefit option that you
can take it within 10 years Radha will dance to
take lump sum votes and you
can take it with your finger or machine after 10 years that
Honorable the total amount you were getting as on
today's date was 10 minutes
amount but you say that instead of today I
want some time every year then you
can share it and you will
get that amount every year according to this percentage which is
David's now let's talk about survival benefit
so if you have served the entire policy term then
you will get its income benefit
that is for the entire policy time if you have
paid the premium for six years then we will pay the
policy system for the year right after that whatever you have
heard of your plan suppose you want to choose till your hour if
you want every option then you will get this income every year
or as you said in this
you will keep getting this income the formula of how the income will be is
written here
but you will not get so much cold  There is no need to do this, if
you take out the term then you
can easily take out all these terms from here
that what is the rate of return that you are getting in
return of money, you will use it, it is
kept here, the transparency is
that you can calculate as per your wish that
if you subscribe on time
and subscribe to Meghnad
first
then I have prepared two lists, one for
income benefit and one for income benefits, let's take a
look at both the term and girlfriend and
also at the calculator,
now let's take a look at the first step,
Sharma ji who is 35 years old is
investing 1 lakh rupees,
he has chosen a premium payment term of eight years,
so his policy term will be 9 years, he has
chosen a benefit from prison progressive, that means it will continue to come to
him for 30 years,
if he subscribes then he pays 1 lakh
rupees as premium for eight years, so
he has a total of eight lakh rupees, please take eight lakh,
after this he will keep getting annual income,
we saw this formula above, till now we got the table, at the very end of it  Rs.
6250 plus if they
give regularly to their team then they will keep getting Rs. 12372 along with loyalty addition,
they will get
money for 30 years, they will get total benefit of
Rs. 20 lakh 58 thousand 750, now
you see that they have invested Rs. 8 lakh
and are getting Rs. 20 lakh 58 thousand 750
plus insurance,
we try to cover this in their example that
what is being received in Italy,
secondly how do you see that
if printed saree is party wear and it is
in the policy then what will happen if there is
death in their share policy then this
channel will get subscription, thirdly that at their place
but here they were getting benefits at
that time, then they will get
subscription in that, basically their death benefit,
but when we talk about getting it, then in the
same way, they have also
got shares and subscription on benefits,
in this you can see we have 27 lakh  You are
getting Rs. 14500 whereas making it Rs. 1 lakh
seems quite lucrative but the
problem is that the annual income here has
reduced and the loyalty addition will also be less if
you see here 250 and 500 and
inside the subscription that if this benefit is
reached then here
first of all we have taken Sharma subscribe
here which is charged in
and in luck it is charged 2.25 so you
take it out from this side which looks something like this it is
written in this fort that if you
subscribe
probx plate 2225% GST will be
charged here all other things are also
written like premium paying term policy time benefit period coffee and here
you will also find that if you commit
suicide then you will get it,
if you die then you will get it and
if you surrender the policy then
look at this, inside here we have
taken one cup of sugar so total time to 8 plus GST keep
this in mind total  rs.6250 subscribe
edition 12345 all of them are getting it, they started subscribing from 10 years
now they are getting it,
307, if we write 307 then they are getting money for 30 years,
if we
talk about total net, what money did they get,
they started getting money,
after that they started getting t-shirt money, that is, the
total money they got was
20 lakh 58 thousand 750 rupees, we collect it properly
in 9486, so you are
getting subscribe 868, how much is this amount, for
how long is your money in it,
you can see these points,
but if you think that 20 lakh 58
thousand, what is important is that you have
received this money in so many years and
what difference does it make to the accused of his murder, that means you are
thinking that you are getting 6250,
but today we have calculated only 6150
here, in the same way as
40 years will continue in the future
When you are getting this money, then its value will be
only 6676 rupees as of today's date, you
must do this and if you
see it in Britain, then it goes further, so
subscribe to them that you should
take the tax benefit,
because of getting it, I was convinced of the returns, I subscribe to
you that you should get returns for the whole year,
this is a subscription, I have just one, do not
waste money just to save tax,
see that you need to log in, let's
try to calculate the value of these three,
if we take these three, if you
take it for the whole year, then the subscription comes out, it is taking a
little amount in it,
you are getting this money, provided that you are
taking it after being in the sentence,
now let's talk, it is very important
that in the beginning you will get the entire amount of ₹1
lakh, but after that you will not
get the sum option here, so whatever happens, it will be calculated,
now let's try to equip the return problem in the same
way, so for the
return of rebel  Inside also one lakh rupees was
given for eight years. Here you
can see that annual income and loyalty addition
as we saw in the first test,
these values ​​have reduced because you are going to get this eight
lakh rupees. If we
go ahead and see here that net,
they had given this money at the beginning
and this money is being returned till the next year, then if we
take it in this, then the return is 5.6 percent. If
you liked what you got, then
see, but mostly when in the last year
after this year, at that time if
you are 35 years old, then you can see that
you are getting money, if we
come at least between four to five, the second thing which
I have already told you,
what will remain in blue, then it is coming to your house,
if we assume 6% impression, then the total
arm hole is coming to you 8 plus this
office benefit. The value of this portal will be
1 lakh ₹500 instead of just 10 lakh, that is, the
value of 1
lakh rupees today  Of course, you will
get the money if you assume 6% interest
as we did in the previous case. Here,
if you calculate the return with tax benefit,
what return will you get by the year 2030, then
it is given here as 5.71. If
you need the link of this Excel sheet,
you will find it in the description below, from
where you can download the Excel sheet and do the
calculation yourself. Now we will
talk about another important topic, that is
discounted rates. That is why
we are doing it after discount benefit. I
have many questions in this way that you
think that you invest the money for 12 years
and after 12 years you can withdraw the entire money.
In this case, what you do is that you invest for eight years
and after eight years you
can withdraw it like this. Now people have this option,
this information is given. I
can say whether it is right or wrong that you can
withdraw the entire money above this, if there is tax benefit then here
he has written it very clearly.
If you take out the lump sum benefit first, you would like to get
lump sum instead of the full income benefit. If you take the lump sum benefit instead of the full income benefit, then
you will
get it at a discounted rate of 8.35%.
What is the discount rate? Let's try to understand the example.
Suppose you
got Rs. 10000000 for 8 to 10 years. If
we apply a discount of 0.5%, then
today you will get only around Rs. 4.5 lakh,
that is, you will not get Rs. 1000000 today,
you will
get only Rs. 4.48 lakh of it. So, the income that you are getting,
your future income, if you had
taken it today,
you would have got less money from Jaipur to Delhi. The most
important thing is that whenever you take a policy,
always go to the company's site and
download this illustration.
You will get answers to all your questions from this illustration.
A very common question that comes
after watching my video is that  If I surrender,
what will I get? In this illustration, it is
written for many that
what is the surrender value? If you are doing the insurance in the second year,
then you have a
guaranteed surrender value of Rs.7000. If you are
doing it in the first year, then it is Rs.105000. And in this way,
they have given what surrender value you will get in the policy term.
Special benefit is also written here, you
can get that too, but it is not guaranteed that you will get
that much benefit, but it is
possible that if you pay the premium
on time and set other terms of the company,
you can also get special benefit based on that,
but this is the maximum amount. As far as
you see, you have paid Rs.2 lakh,
but you are getting only Rs.6206. Therefore,
taking back the money through Life Enjoy Insurance is a very difficult
task. Some small things are covered,
wide benefits and side
effects, if you
keep subscribing, then you will keep getting additions.
Before taking the policy, you must know these things, in all these things,
you may find the video very long.  The
question arises as to how much percentage value loan can be obtained in the interview, so I
wanted to cover some of these things in today's video. Is it for subscribing or
not? If you liked this video, then do like it and do
not
forget to subscribe to my channel so that you keep getting more such videos.
Do tell me by commenting
if you have any
Bluetooth settings plan and
why you have taken that line. I will come soon with another
video. Till then keep saving the money, keep
coming. Recovery money matters.